Background Music.
How is quantum Computing different.
Quantum Computing builds upon the weird
behavior of quantum physics
but don't worry quantum physics is
explained in simple language in this
course
and after you complete the course
quantum physics will not appear weird
the notion of a bit is different in
Quantum computing.
A Quantum bit is not just off or on it
can be in superposition
bits are not independent of each other
they can be entangled
there is a fundamental difference in the
way we program quantum computers
it is not based on the fond human
architecture
one human architecture is the idea that
there is a CPU which performs
computations on data stored in memory
the CPU plus memory model doesn't apply
to quantum computers.
Quantum computers are designed like a
digital circuit with Gates
instead of bits the gates operate on
Quantum bits.
Quantum bits are called qubits
the qubits are not independent
they can be superposed and entangled
with each other
superposition and entanglement requires
us to rethink algorithms in a
fundamental way
programming quantum computers involves
math
but don't worry this course explains all
the required math in simple language
it can be understood by any software
professional.
It is enough if you know 10th grade math
everything you need to know is explained
in this course.